<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-04T09:34:21-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">meometer’s blog | Tiles</title><subtitle>What the heck. Let's invent time travel.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Leutentent</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/self-awareness/technology/hci/2017/11/27/leutentent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leutentent" /><published>2017-11-27T03:04:04-07:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T03:04:04-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/self-awareness/technology/hci/2017/11/27/leutentent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/self-awareness/technology/hci/2017/11/27/leutentent.html">&lt;!-- calls to action --&gt;

&lt;!-- local --&gt;

&lt;!-- external --&gt;

&lt;!-- images --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 3 months I lived without internet like a feral beast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got wired over the weekend, fencing in my corner of the West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will this be the last time I’m ever not wired?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dances-with-http&quot;&gt;Dances With HTTP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leutenent Dunbar, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0099348/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot;&gt;Dances With Wolves&lt;/a&gt;, requests an assignment out West to experience the dying phenomenon of wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, I don’t carry a phone so I can experience the dying phenomenon of human wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://meometer.github.io/assets/image-dances-with-wolves-001.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dances With Wolves&quot; title=&quot;Dances With Wolves 001&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This decade hit an inflection point because to the best of my knowledge I am the only remaining human over 12 years old without a phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime around puberty every young &lt;em&gt;homo sapien sapien&lt;/em&gt; gets handed a phone by their parents and they evolve into &lt;em&gt;homo sapien wired&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-phones&quot;&gt;No Phones&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://meometer.github.io/assets/image-edna-no-capes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Edna&quot; title=&quot;Edna&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save for two phones purchased for development, I lived without mobiles my entire life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t misunderstand me, they’re amazing! A supercomputer in my pocket with permanent access to all humanity’s collective knowledge?! (And disfunction.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not for me because far too easily they knock me off balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;balance&quot;&gt;Balance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, like me, you fall under the moniker &lt;em&gt;homo sapien sapien&lt;/em&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;homo sapien wired&lt;/em&gt;) sometimes balance can be tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get out of balance even now at my geologic age when I should be as wise and steady as a Galapagos tortoise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple recipe for disaster which I can whip up on a moments notice consists of: 1) infinite curiousity (ding!), 2) infinite access to infinite information (oh, shiny, shiny internet!), and 3) non-infinite self awareness and self control (guilty!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a phone, I live permanently inside that disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now, just getting back online after a long break, I fiercely have to keep myself in check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My social media diet consists only of twitter. Makes sense, it owns the tightest constraints: &lt;em&gt;get your idea across in 140/280 chars&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond how it makes people get to the point, I like how well I can track specific subjects I enjoy like  &lt;em&gt;technology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;art&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;astronomy&lt;/em&gt;, and, ugh, &lt;em&gt;politics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Politics. My lifelong fascination with this bloody nonsense exists due to my curiousity around how our species works for and against itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, my first wired weekend in forever, I checked twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A handful of political dramas on which I keep my eye grew and shifted and escalated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every 110 minutes, &lt;em&gt;Anything new?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already track potentially wasted time with a &lt;em&gt;Project&lt;/em&gt; in meometer called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;negative&lt;/code&gt; (aka Negative Habits) and, in this case, an &lt;em&gt;Intent&lt;/em&gt; labeled &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;browse twitter politics&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By defining this &lt;em&gt;Intent&lt;/em&gt; I was/am conciously forced to decide: Is this — &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;browsing twitter politics&lt;/code&gt;, something which lives light-years beyond my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/Q/What_is_a_'sphere_of_influence'&quot;&gt;sphere of influence&lt;/a&gt; — a good use of my time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is. Sometimes it is the optimal use of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read something which dispels a growing story in my mind, or a joke which releases some anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I stumble across an answer to a coding issue I have and shave 30 hours of frustration off my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is a limit to the time assigned you, and if you don’t use it to free yourself it will be gone and never return.
&lt;br /&gt;‐ Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These twitter checks happened between studying technology, code commits, prose commits, playing guitar, and playing with the critter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which &lt;em&gt;Actions&lt;/em&gt;, do you think, make me more proud: 1) Screwing off on twitter to scratch some knuckleheaded itch or 2) the moments when I grew and created and played?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My twitter checks have grown both less frequent and shorter because I started tracking in meometer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paradox-or-irony&quot;&gt;Paradox or Irony?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny thing about my little human wilderness idear: I need fences, and I know I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need a reminder life is finite, that I live in a &lt;em&gt;timebox&lt;/em&gt; called a lifetime, that I can never get a day back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need a constant reminder because I can so easily get lost in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need &lt;em&gt;The Line&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oh, yeah, good news! &lt;em&gt;The Line&lt;/em&gt; is back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Before our eyes, the wilderness and the wilderness of humanity recedes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enemy Mind</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/problem/bias/self-awareness/solution/cognitive-bias/2017/11/19/enemy-mind.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enemy Mind" /><published>2017-11-19T15:16:16-07:00</published><updated>2017-11-19T15:16:16-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/problem/bias/self-awareness/solution/cognitive-bias/2017/11/19/enemy-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/problem/bias/self-awareness/solution/cognitive-bias/2017/11/19/enemy-mind.html">&lt;p&gt;I concluded my mind is my enemy, and, because of the bias generated in my grey matter, your mind is your enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this sounds harsh, so let me clarify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean it’s out to kill you, &lt;strong&gt;I mean it’s out to trick you at every turn&lt;/strong&gt;, and because of our minds’ stealth, we miss the machinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t believe me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s walk through a little thing called &lt;strong&gt;cognitive bias&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cognitive-bias&quot;&gt;Cognitive Bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The super duper offical definition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;””&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translation: &lt;em&gt;Your mind is your enemy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dozens. Hundreds. Thousands. More? of these little bastards live in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squatters who lie to us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like bloatware on a 2006 HP Laptop or bloatware on a 2017 HP Laptop, they come preinstalled whether we want ‘em or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each bias is like a scared, crotchety, old switchboard operator with an agenda: they have a belief and want to promote it to us like an aggressive missionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biases work like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they deliberately disguise information (&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;example 01&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;example 02&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;example 03&lt;/a&gt;, et. al.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they deliberately over-emphasize info aligning with it’s belief (hyperawareness, rationalization, people exploit this intentionally)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and they fight like Terminators until dead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t want our minds full of uninvited liars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fewer biases means a more accurate view of everything. We become better&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;im-a-good-driver&quot;&gt;“I’m a Good Driver.”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As meometer marches to profitability I work reception at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://learntodrivecolorado.com&quot;&gt;drive school&lt;/a&gt; in the Front Range. (When it’s quiet I automate every last task I can with Python which is ludicrously fun.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People come in to take permit tests and drive tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When explaining what they need 3 out of 5 adults — not quite Trident gum numbers — say the exact same phrase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;                    GEOFFREY THE RECEPTIONIST
    Good afternoon. How can I help you?

                    ADULT CUSTOMER
    So I need to take a driver's test
    because...{reason number 9}

                    GEOFFREY THE RECEPTIONIST
    Great. May I see your permi—

                    ADULT CUSTOMER
    I'm a good driver.

                    GEOFFREY THE RECEPTIONIST
    Brilliant. No need to test you then because
    you know every last thing about automobiles,
    automobile maintenance, traffic patterns,
    handling in adverse weather conditions, and
    have all 498 Colorado traffic statutes
    memorized, correct?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I never say that last bit.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do I trust they’re a good driver? Of course not, because their opinion is driven by their mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their lying, duplicitous mind. The biases exhibited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I trust the Examiners with their external observations. (And their education.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ THIS IS THE THESIS: ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to get outside of one’s own way to get a critical view of actions in general let alone something so habituated as &lt;em&gt;driving&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After more than 30 years of locked in habits (in my case), how the hell would I know if I’m a good driver? And what if my first and only instructor was completely bananas?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;                    TERRIBLE INSTRUCTOR
    You should try to jump your van on the
    railroad tracks over by the prison. It's
    even better on a motorcycle without a helmet.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biases behave like organisms, defending themselves to the point of ignoring reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened in front of me three weeks ago:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;                    EXAMINER
    You failed your test because you didn't
    stop at the stop sign at 14th and Ford.

                    DRIVER
    I didn't see a stop sign!

                    EXAMINER
    Exactly.

                    DRIVER
    You're wrong. There was no stop sign!

                    EXAMINER
    I've driven this route 173 times.

                    DRIVER
    But, there's no stop sign!

                    EXAMINER
    I designed the route. It's my favorite, ever, in 31 years of doing this.

                    DRIVER
    This is bullshit! I'm a great driver!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess how many people have said, “I’m not a very good driver.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% of people surveyed — or not surveyed because I have &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; asked — believe they’re a good driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because they listen to the whispers of their enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the mathematical formula for their belief: &lt;em&gt;I am a good driver&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know who Csaba Cere is.
I have never been to a car race.
I do not change my own oil.
I have never checked the pressure on my tires and have no idea what they’re at right now.
I do not watch any F1, Kart, Rally, Motorcycle, or Nascar races.
I have never had a subscription to Car &amp;amp; Driver or Road and Track.
I don’t know there’s a channel on my tv called Speed.
I do not know how many traffic laws exist.
I have no idea how much torque is put to my back wheels.
(Also, what’s torque, and why would I, a driver, care?)
I have never driven a right handed car.
Nor have I driven in a foreign land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore (or a formula in LaTeX)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these folks really mean is: “I can adequately operate a handful of cars.” (No standards, no right-hand drives, nothing rear wheel drive and turbo, no busses, no semis, no motorcycles…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-monster&quot;&gt;“You monster.”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while I make a startling claim and watch the horror in a Customer’s eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A debate starts between Customer and Examiner where the professionally trained, educated expert tries to explain a concept only to have the ignorant (proper definition) Customer attempt to correct the expert who is inarguably right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Customer needs backup for their completely wrong assumption they turn to me, the receptionist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say, “I’m the worst driver in here,” and watch their circuits fuse because this is the first time they have &lt;strong&gt;ever&lt;/strong&gt; heard this sentence. It does not compute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Customer’s head angle straightens out, I follow up with, “When it comes to drive testing I trust the professionally trained expert’s opinion and knowledge on what the State says is the right way to do things.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes my comments recalibrate their minds and helps them recognize they don’t even know the criteria they’re getting tested on, let alone the DMV’s position on what’s correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;false-positives&quot;&gt;False Positives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our biases, like 5 person sub-reddits, latch onto anything and everything which backs their beliefs while ignoring and dispelling anything which disproves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these methods for distorting truth is the &lt;em&gt;false positive&lt;/em&gt;, taking credit for something unrelated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do something wrong or do something unrelated, see a good result an intentionally [mis-correlate/causate]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happens in any domain: poker, investing, relationships, life…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your internal dialogue starts with, “I finally got this figured out!”, I’ll bet you’re guided by a bias. (And about to learn a life lesson.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-big&quot;&gt;“That’s Big.”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;image: Steve Martin and Audrey II&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only talked about a handful of types. Here’s a list of known, defined biases. Here’s another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That’s big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things pop up like exoplanets both in definition and in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exploitability&quot;&gt;Exploitability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With multiple ways to stroke each bias — keywords, arguments, emotional ploys, and more — organizations and individuals use &lt;em&gt;Behavioral Science&lt;/em&gt; to drive your behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around formally since &lt;em&gt;rhetoric&lt;/em&gt; in ancient Greece, nowadays &lt;em&gt;Behavioral Science&lt;/em&gt; is supercharged with AI and infinite flops and &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;psychographic maps&lt;/a&gt; and better-than-free, ubiquitous delivery directly to our faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dfence&quot;&gt;D:fence:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One defense against this, against getting hijacked, is having fewer and weaker biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use meometer to 1) study them via &lt;em&gt;Nudges&lt;/em&gt; and 2) catalog them in the real world via a &lt;em&gt;Project&lt;/em&gt; called &lt;em&gt;biascatcher&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These practices help distance myself, allowing for clearer thinking and a chance to dispel them in myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Geoffrey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. I’m a good driver.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Getting out of one's own way to get a critical view of actions in general is pert near impossible, let alone with something so habituated as driving.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Negative a Billion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/feedback/release/nps/2017/10/27/negative-a-billion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Negative a Billion" /><published>2017-10-27T07:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T07:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feedback/release/nps/2017/10/27/negative-a-billion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/feedback/release/nps/2017/10/27/negative-a-billion.html">&lt;p&gt;You know those emails you get which ask only one thing: “On a scale of 1 to 10, how likely are you to recommend &lt;em&gt;whatever&lt;/em&gt;…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answers to this question produce a metric called a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netpromoter.com/know/&quot;&gt;Net Promoter Score&lt;/a&gt;, a measure of the likelihood a User will talk about your amazing product. It’s incredibly useful, higher is better and you can get negative scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.netpromoter.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/NPS-Definition-copy-04-copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image for ranges&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on a scale of 1 to 10, I gave our v2-beta-1 a score of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;negative it sucks so bad it’s not even a number&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; which then threw off our cumulative NPS score for the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Personally, I was hoping for a 4.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Totally my fault, of course!&lt;/strong&gt; Augh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’d we learn with this painful first release?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-show-stopping-ux-issues&quot;&gt;1) Show Stopping UX Issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A trifecta of pain-in-the-butt-to-use issues top the list on the &lt;em&gt;Let’s Take Another Run At This Before Releasing Into More Hands&lt;/em&gt; board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learnings:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let the sauce simmer some more. It ain’t ready yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-show-stopping-bugs&quot;&gt;2) Show Stopping Bugs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documented and prioritized. Nothing’s a killer with biggest challenge already fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learnings:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Up our testing game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-design-dissonance&quot;&gt;3) Design Dissonance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting with meometer v2-beta-1, using it, always finding my head a little sideways when I did, I realized v2’s current UI lives about 179.97 degrees from where we’re heading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dictated by both the death of v1’s technology and our new tech stack for v2, the path from &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;release&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;v3&lt;/em&gt; winds more than Joyce’s Ulysses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iibawards-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/projects/images/000/000/193/large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dublin or whatever.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This galactic dissonance inspired meometer’s &lt;em&gt;The Design Manifesto&lt;/em&gt; to encapsulate &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;. This way, when we’re limited by time/talent/resources we’re still aimed in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u4ZoJKF_VuA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learnings:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Result: meometer’s &lt;em&gt;The Design Manifesto&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Result: The new &lt;em&gt;Lap Review&lt;/em&gt; design which centered around a value from the manifesto, &lt;em&gt;Slap Jack Fast™&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-to-work&quot;&gt;Back to Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;v2-beta-2 reverts back — I’m using it already — to a desktop application, and still needs attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some general grooming of our website and such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to work for me, and #doNotCarriacou*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;br /&gt;
Geoffrey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*I’ll tell the story some day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Hillsborough_Bay,_Carriacou.jpeg#/media/File:Hillsborough_Bay,_Carriacou.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/07/Hillsborough_Bay%2C_Carriacou.jpeg/1200px-Hillsborough_Bay%2C_Carriacou.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Hillsborough Bay, Carriacou.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hillsborough Bay, Carriacou - By &lt;a href=&quot;//commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?title=User:Deeferdiving&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;redlink=1&quot; class=&quot;new&quot; title=&quot;User:Deeferdiving (page does not exist)&quot;&gt;Deeferdiving&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;span class=&quot;int-own-work&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Own work&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0&quot; title=&quot;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 4.0&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=46108061&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;


excerpt_separator: &lt;!--more--&gt;


Excerpt
&lt;!--more--&gt;

excerpt: &quot;In which we admonish our pathetic release like a [@geoffrey: comedy goes here.]&quot;


Hey now.

Out-of-excerpt
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In which we admonish our pathetic release like a [@geoffrey: comedy goes here].</summary></entry></feed>